All right. It seems like before in the meeting.
OK, that's all right. So thanks for joining
today. So today we are having the third session
on Super Luminal Communication Voice Codec
project. And this is focusing on solving your
problems and any questions you can get solved.
So. I'm Dhruvishka, your teaching assistant
for the project and as well as the proxy client
of the project. And our project client is MapTek.
So moving forward, so before we start, I would
like to give you a brief introduction on the
project. This is how I articulate the project
and the title. So the project is Superluminal
Communication Voice Codec, which means if we
segregate this into three parts, as superluminal
communication, which means communicating faster
than the speed of light. And up to now with
the current technology feasibilities, this
is considered as physically incapable. So scientists
are thinking of a solution to reach, at least
to reach that level up to a certain point. So
they have come up with a theoretical solution
called wormholes. where it is created in the
space to travel from one end to another end
within a minimum time. And this concept, still
it's in the conceptual level, but it could
not be able to produce without a huge investment.
Even though we have created such a wormhole
in the space, at the initial phase of this kind
of a solution, we cannot test that with some
human beings. So that's why we are trying to
pass this as an initial step. We are trying
to pass some messages through this created wormhole.
as you can see there's a tunnel kind of thing
in this wormhole. So it's believed that if we
try to send a message from one end to another
end we can pass this message. But why cannot
we pass human beings like that or a spaceship
to travel in between these two places because
these wormholes are considered really small.
and spaceship kind of things cannot be passed
through that. That's and if we try to wider
this size of the wormhole, it is like really,
really costly. We have to do a bigger investments
on that. So what we are trying to do is passing
some information. Hence, we are trying to creating
this voice coding. which means we are trying
to pass a audio file a compressed audio file
from one end to another end where in one end
we are trying to encode it and pass it through
the tunnel and at the other end of the tunnel
this the one who is receiving the message can
decode it and listen to the message you sent.
So simply this is what you have to do. So there's
a program written by you, which has two functionalities.
One is encoding, and the other one is decoding.
So once a person encode, input a file, let's
say, voice.wav file. And he or she tries to
encode it. And while passing through the program,
it will be compressed and will create a payload
bit. And once this payload bin is passed through
to the receiver, he or she can decode this
payload and then come up with the output, which
means the voice out dot wave file. So here's
the entire picture that we can see of how the
things work. So. like I said previously voice.pale
input file comes and it is encoded using your
command encode and it is saved as a payload
bin and the one who receives that payload bin
use the command decode and then create the
output file. So when compressing this file it
could be Sometimes let's say you might be able
to compress this file to the hundred percent
or at least to ninety percent ninety five percent
but it doesn't ensure that you the one who is
receiving that file once it is decoded it doesn't
ensure that he or she can play back and understand
the message that you that consists the file
correctly. So we have to identify the sweet
point in between this compression rate and
the fidelity. So accuracy as if you if you listen
to the kickoff meeting by you know professor
Simon. So he's explaining it's not implemented
yet. So we have to do some trial and errors
to understand this. most feasible solution for
this compression rate and the fidelity rate.
So with that understanding let's go to the project
aim. So here the project aim is developing
sorry developing sorry again developing a highly
efficient voice encoder and decoder with maximal
compression and high intelligibility. What do
we mean by intelligibility here? It is once
you receive the file, once you decode that file,
you should be able to replay that and understand
the message that consists the file. So these
are the functional requirement details shared
by our client. So you can name your file as
name.py if you are using a Python script. Or
if you are using a standalone executable, it
can be named as name.exe. And these are the
encoding and decoding steps that you need to
follow. You have the file and you have a command
called encode. And once the input file is given,
you have to create the payload. And in the
same application, you have to have the decoding
step password. So file is there. Once you put
the decoding command, you can, using that payload
file, payload.bin, you can decode it and create
the output.bin file. And apart from that, if
there are any other dependencies coming up
with your script or the.exe file, you have to
zip all together and create this file and make
it as a name.zip. And this program should be
run on a virtual machine running Windows on
Azure. And apart from that, this single channel
LPCM sampled at 44.1 kilohertz with 16 bits
per sample and we are using some voice human
voice audio for this one. So the project deliverables
are the encoding algorithm, decoding algorithm
and the documentation of each process. Here
I have given you some sample user stories, you
don't have to specifically stick into that.
You can create any number of user stories as
we go forward and feel free to get some sort
of an idea or the format that you have to maintain
when you are creating user stories as a best
practice here. So one example is as a user,
I want to upload a.wav file. the codecs so
that I can encode the input file. So as a user
or as the person who is using this program
I want to what I really need there and so that
what I can achieve. So that's the format that
we are maintaining and for each and every user
story it's better to have an acceptance criteria
which gives what is client expecting. after
using this user story. And there are a few
other user stories I have shared with you, like
three of them. Yeah. And I would like to say
a word about the upcoming sessions as well.
Now, this will be the last Q&A session we are
having today. And going forward, we will be
having one-to-one client meetings with each
group and a client meeting will be where I represent
the client as the proxy client and you'll be
given 25 minutes each team bi-weekly we will
be having this meeting. We are going like a
sprint in here.
the processes that everything is following a
Jazz Chrome practice and any, you know. any
assignments and everything that some need to
submit. It's going like reports that you need
to provide. It's going like sprint wise. So
I think from 12th August onward, we can start
our meetings. And you have to share the, you
have to take the responsibility of sharing
and organizing a meeting and share that link
with me. So once I share my schedule with you,
you can allocate a time for your own team. And
that time slot is fixed for all the meetings.
And yeah, what else? So yeah, in these kind
of meetings, we are going to discuss about
how you have been able to do this. plan the
next meeting what you have done in the previous
meeting. So to facilitate that I think a GitHub
reports will be created. Today hopefully I
will try to create the groups for each and every
team. Yeah that's the information I want to
share with you guys. So if you have any questions
regarding that or any
going to be how this journey is going to be.
Just let me know and anything you need to clarify
I'm happy to help. Thank you.
Um, so when you said the meeting, is it, is
it next week? We're supposed to have availability
with you or is it a week after? Because it's
a, it's a bi-weekly, right? Yes. Bi-weekly
one. Uh, I hope, uh, as for the calendar in
the homepage, I think it's, it will start on,
uh, fourth week on what the beginning of the
spring one. Uh, In there, you have to submit
the initial report as well as the snapshot 1.1,
if I'm correct, yes, right? Yep, that's really
good. Yes, I need to confirm that whether it's
starting from 12 August onward, that we can
have the meetings, or else it would be 19th
August. I hope it's 12th. So I just need to
confirm that with Dr. Amali. Yeah. Okay. Yeah,
because the so the initial report is due on
the Sunday 18th, right? So that's it'll be before
the initial report then is due. Um, I'm not
pretty sure about the deadline of it, uh, because.
Yeah, just need to. Yep. I'm not pretty sure
about that. Just let me check. Yeah, that's
okay.
Yeah. Up to now I couldn't find the place of
where it's mentioned as the deadline. Yeah.
I will once it is, once I found that I will
share the information with you. That's good.
Thank you.
Anything else?
Hi, is there going to be data provided to us?
I hope. Up to now, there's no file shared with
me, but I can have a chat with the client and
let you know. But up to now, you can initiate
with some freely available resources, right?
Yeah, all right, thanks.
And anyone else? Any other questions?
I do have a quick question. I'm not too sure
if they answered this in the kickoff meeting,
but in the actual document, it says the input
file. There's nothing else is known about the
content of the input file. It's only known that
it's a human voice. We can assume it's still
English, right? We don't have to do any other
languages. Good question. Yeah, let's assume
for the time being it's coming in English. Yeah,
again.
I got one more question. When it says we are
using Azure for the actual codec, do we in
the group have to ever use it or is it just
during demos and the final, it's just running
on it? Yes, I've known this, the thing is, sorry,
Dylan, right? So the thing is you have to come
up with a demonstration kind of thing in each.
meeting not at the initial meeting but afterwards
it's better to come up with some demonstration
on what you what you have done so far. That's
how it's going right. And when it comes to a
sprint meeting, sprint planning you're showing
the client that this kind of thing has done
and getting the feedback and based on that
feedback you are trying to improve your product
right. So I think we can follow the same practice
here, like we did last time. So yes, it's better
if you can come up with some, up to some level,
if you can come up with the product that can
demonstrate. So that would be great, yes. Super.
Anyone else?
Yeah, I just wondering, is this just a free-for-all?
We're not going to get any guidance to how
we incorporate the AI into this codec? Or will
there be more resources down the line with
how about they expect us to do this? Oh, you
mean like, should we focus on the deadlines
or should we focus on the product completing
the product, you say? Um, I not, not necessarily.
Um, I guess. Yeah. I, well with like how sprint
is set up, like you just have to have a working
thing. It doesn't really matter how up to how
complete it is. You just have to have something
that works by the time the sprint. Um, happens.
Yeah. If you, if you are interested in the
competition that, uh, the, the competition information
shared by a map tech. And if you are targeting
that it's better to, you know, completing the
product while meeting your deadlines. If you're
really focusing on, but anyway, it's encouraged
to come up with the complete product at the
end, right? Because we are, we are doing as
a project. So it's, it's better to complete
as much as possible, which means like some tangible
product that we need. So.
I would suggest have a proper plan at the initial
stage because this is the right time to discuss
with your teammates and identify each and everyone's
skills and if you are lacking some resources
try to educate them or try to give them some
guidance like those who have the knowledge
share that in between. Try to plan properly
using this couple of days and from there onwards
it will be easier for you to like with a less
struggle on completing the product and meeting
the deadlines. So I would suggest to you know
come up with a proper plan after discussing
with your teammates. Try to write the user stories
from here onwards after eliciting all the requirements
that currently have been provided. Did I answer
your question?
I think, yeah, that was, yeah. All right.
Anything else?
Sorry, I keep asking questions. Okay, that's
okay. That's why the session is for. Yes. So,
you know, we do, they do mention like the super-illuminal
communication aspect of it. How important,
because it's like, it's not really in the project
itself that like we have to do, well, the compression
part, but in the actual reporting, do we have
to like reference it a lot? Like, oh. do the
super luminal communication, we have to do the
compression. Like, do we, because even in like
the user stories you provide, it's not really
mentioned, the like the super luminal communication.
I just want to know how important it is to like
put that to the forefront, you know? Yeah,
let's figure it out like this. So. The story
behind this project is what I explained at
the very beginning of my presentation. Right.
And that is what the story shared by Professor
Simon as well. Underneath such a concept or
such a solution, there could be multiple usages.
Right. Yeah. Not this one, but you know, for
our day-to-day activities, there could be some
more usages starting from a solution like this.
Yeah. So let's focus on that part rather than,
you know, coming up with like, going to the
extreme level and saying this superluminant
communication. Like, it's like the additional
information that you have provided on the project.
Yeah. Right? So it's like, I'll tell you. Yes,
so we are trying to reach that level. But up
to now, we are starting from a very low level
and try to build up the product from a very
low level and try to build up on top of that.
Okay, that makes sense, yeah. Yeah, so it's
really just like, it's not really the forefront
of the actual project. It's just kind of like
motivation, kind of like, oh, that's where we're
heading. But right now we're here. Okay. Some
sort of thing. Yes. Yeah.
Anyone else? Do you have any other questions?
right. If you have further questions just feel
free to reach me. I think my email is provided
in the homepage so you can directly email me
or I'll try to create the groups today. I hope
I have received the Teams access since I don't
have in I'll try to create those groups. And
from there onwards, you can use those channels
to communicate with me, clarify your doubts,
and share your meeting links and everything.
You can use those groups. Yeah, if we don't
have further questions, we can wind up from
here.
That'd be good. I'm all good if everyone else
is.
Thank you. All right then. Thanks everyone for
joining today. See you in upcoming meetings.
Good luck. Thank you.